Finding Aid for the Program for Art on Film Records, 1951-1999, undated IA20008
Institutional Records and Archives
- Program for Art on Film and Production Laboratory records, 1971-1999; (bulk 1984-1994); Series I.; 67 Linear Feet; (circa 71 boxes)
  - Publications and publication information, 1984-1998; Series I.B.; 18.75 Linear Feet; (18 boxes)
    - Art on Screen ("Critical Inventory"):
      - Crit Inventory Article, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-98A)
      - Critical Inventory: Specifications, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-98A)
    - East-West Film Journal, December 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-102)
      [Reprints; multiple copies.]
    - Films on Art:
      - Films on Art Bibliography, 1994 Edition (Box 2004.IA.14-86 and 87)
        [3 copies.]
      - FoA Bibliography: Updates, etc., 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - FoA Bibliography: Intl Festivals, 1987-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - FoA Bibliography: various editions (file copies), undated (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
    - "Films and Videos on Photography", 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-102)
    - Film descriptions, video guide, 1988; 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
      [Program for Art on Film: 1988 Productions (typescript, 8 copies); Art on Film/Film on Art Video Guide.]
    - Newsletters:
      - Newsletter, Vol. 1 No. 1 Development ISSNs, 1990-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 1 No. 1 Spring 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 2 Fall 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 3 Winter 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 2, No. 1 Spring 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 2, No. 2 Fall 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 1 Spring 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 1 Working File, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 2 Fall/Winter 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 4, No. 1 Spring/Summer 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
      - File Copies: Newsletter, Vol. 4, No. 2 Fall/Winter 1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-94)
    - [Miscellaneous publications], 1987; 1992,; 1994,; 1998 (Box 2004.IA.14-102)
      [Film and Video in Museums: Results of a 1987 Survey conducted by the Program for Art on Film (multiple copies); Art on Film/Film on Art video series brochures (multiple copies); Art on Film Database: Subject Index Members' Edition (multiple copies); Art on Film Database: Subject Index (multiple copies); Guidelines for Evaluating Films on Art (multiple copies); Laboratoire et banque de données de films sur l'art: Art on Film (multiple copies); Film and Video at the Metropolitan Museum of Art (multiple copies); Program for Art on Film press folder (2 copies).]
    - Photograph releases:
      - A, 1991; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - B, 1991; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - C, 1991; 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - D, 1991-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - E, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - F, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - G, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - H, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - I, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - J, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - K and L, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - M, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - N, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - O, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - P, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - Q, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - R, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - S, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - T, U, and V, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - W, 1991-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - X, Y, Z [empty folder], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - [Photos and release forms], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
    - Publication Files:
      - Art and Film Articles by John Read, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Getty Publication Services, 1993-1995 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - AAUP Info (from Getty Pubs.), 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - MMA Annual Report, 1993-1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Trust Report, 1993-1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - PAF Publication Projects, 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Photo Release Form, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - AHIP Bulletin article, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Articles to write/place, 1987; 1988,; 1990,; 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Sightlines article, 1987; 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - H. Montgomery article, "History and Genres,", 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-116)
      - Pratt Agreement: Drafts, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - Rejects, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-123)
      - Cities and Cinema filmography: reprint from East West Film Journal, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn. Comps and Press Copies, P.R., 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn. Research/Editorial Work, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn.: Basia Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn.: Order Form and Mailing, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn. Typesetting/Printing, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Photo Pubn. In-House Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - D. Pignetti: Photo Book Film Sales, 1992-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Art History and Film: original rpt., undated (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Biblio: Update, 1994-1997 (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
      - Untitled folder [book jackets, fiscal codes], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-124)
  - Art on Film/Film on Art records, 1984-1998; Series I.C.; 25.5 Linear Feet; (29 boxes)
    Organization
    These records are organized in three subseries:
    Series I.C.1. Production records, 1984-1994
    Series I.C.2. Film and video, 1988-1992 and undated
    Series I.C.3. Promotional materials, 1986-1998.
    Records consist of photographs, correspondence, letters, contracts and legal documents, invoices, press materials, film treatments, photographs, awards for films, films, an audiocassette, and clippings, produced for and by the Program for Art on Film and its Production Laboratory, 1984-1998. The records describe the production, evaluation and promotion of the 14 films produced by the Program for Art on Film in a series entitled Art on Film/Film on Art. Among the artists, art historians and filmmakers who collaborated on some of these films are David Hockney, Sir Ernst Gombrich, and Philip Haas, and the records include correspondence and other documents relating to these individuals. The 14 films, which are included in the records, are: Architecture of Transcendence: Beauvais Cathedral; Painted Earth: The Art of the Mimbres Indians; The Fayum Portraits: Funerary Painting of Roman Egypt; 1867: The Execution of Maximilian; Leonardo's Deluge; MA: Space/Time in the Garden of Ryoan-ji; St. Genevieve, Pantheon of Domes; Gombrich Themes: Part 1, Illuminations in Art and Nature; Gombrich Themes: Part 2, Reflection in Art and Nature; A Mosque in Time, A Window to Heaven; Giorgione's Tempest; A Day on the Grand Canal with the Emperor of China; Trevi; De Artificiali Perspectiva or Anamorphosis; and St. Neophytos and Icons of Wishful Thinking. Information on the evaluation process for the films is also included in the records, as are awards in the form of plaques, certificates and statuettes presented to the Program for Art on Film for some of these productions. The promotional materials include press kits, testimonials and fan mail for all Program for Art on Film publications and productions.
    - Production records, Series I.C.1.; approx. 11.5 linear feet 14 boxes
      Records consist of photographs, correspondence, contracts and legal documents, invoices, press materials, film treatments, photographs and awards for films produced for and by the Program for Art on Film and its Production Laboratory, 1984-1994. The records describe the production and evaluation of the 14 films produced by the Program for Art on Film.
      Arrangement note
      These records are listed in general subject order, and in the order found within the original accession.
      Restrictions on Access
      Contains financial and personal information.
      - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88B)
        [Maximilian photos/pasteups (in gray envelope); Cormack/Maben contact sheets (in folder); St. Neophytos transparences (in folder)]
      - Correspondence, contracts, invoices, press materials, for A Day on the Grand Canal, Anamorphosis, Architecture of Transcendence, 1867: Execution of Maximilian, The Fayum Portraits, Giorgione's Tempest, Gombrich's Themes:
        - Hockney Hass Problems, 1987-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Grand Canal: Legal, 1987-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - A Day on the Grand Canal/Hockney/Haas, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Grand Canal, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - A Day on the Grand Canal/Hockney/Haas, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - A Day on the Grand Canal/Hockney/Haas, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - A Day on the Grand Canal/Hockney/Haas, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Grand Canal/BBC, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Anamorphosis: Treatments, 1987; 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Griffiths, Quay, Cardinal Anamorphosis Treatment: preproduction, 1987-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Griffiths, Quay, Cardinal Anamorphosis Production, 1989-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Sir Ernst Gombrich/Anamorphosis, 1989-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Griffiths/Brothers Quay/Cardinal Anamorphic Art, 1988-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - R/Greenberg/Beauvais Deliverables, 1987-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - 1867/Contracts, etc., 1989; 1990,; 1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - 1867, 1990-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Syddal-McMullen-Wilson: The Execution of Maximilian, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89A)
        - Bob Rosen/Fayum Portraits Deliverables, 1987-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Bill Cran/Giorgione Deliverables, 1988-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Hockney/Haas Deliverables, 1987; 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence and deliverables, Anamorphosis, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, Transcendence, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Sydall/McMullen/Wilson Maximilian Deliverables, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, 1867: Execution of Maximilian, 1990-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, The Fayum Portraits, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, Giorgione's Tempest, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Gombrich Themes Deliverables, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, Gombrich Themes, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
        - Post-production correspondence, A Day on the Grand Canal etc. [empty folder], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-89B)
      - Production Lab deliverables:
        - Iimura/Isozaki/MA deliverables, 1988-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Haas, Philip, 1988-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Mark Whitney/Leonardo Deliverables, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Anthology Correspondence: Lee, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Compilation Tape, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Wraparound Production, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Day on Grand Canal Press/PR, 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Anita Thacher, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Film/Video Laboratories, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Audio Plus Video: NJ, 1990-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Metrocolor London Ltd., 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Donna Ahlstrand, 1986; 1988-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Wraparound Producver: Shigekawa, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Wraparound Director: Camerini, 1990-1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Invoices and Releases, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Wraparound Production, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Art on Film/Film on Art Panelists Resumes, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Budget: Lab anthology, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Production costs survey, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Janis Klein Lab Film Video Compilation, 1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Other Consultants, 1984-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90A)
        - Post-production correspondence Leonardo's Deluge, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence MA: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji, 1990-1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Dodds/Velez Cordoba Deliverables, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence, A Mosque in Time, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Dodds/Velez Great Mosque, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Thacher/Brody: Deliverables, 1988-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence Painted Earth: the Art of the Mimbres Indians, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Descendre/Bergdoll St. Genevieve Deliverables, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence St. Genevieve, the Pantheon of Domes, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Bergdoll/Descendre: Dome of the Parisian Pantheon, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Cormack/Maben St. Neophytos Deliverables, 1989-1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence, A Window to Heaven, 1990-1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Cormack/Maben: Caves of Neophytos, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Dick Rogers/Trevi Fountain Deliverables, 1987-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Post-production correspondence, Trevi, 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
        - Art on Film/Film on Art Deliverables - Camerini, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-90B)
      - Production Lab correspondence:
        - Ma: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji Iimura/Isozaki Research, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Ma: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji Iimura/Isozaki Research #2, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Ma: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji Iimura/Isozaki biographies, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Ma: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji Iimura/Isozaki, 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Ma: Space/Time in Garden of Ryoan-ji Iimura/Isozaki treatments, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Taka and his Film Festivals, 1990-1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Ma: Space/Time (Lee's), 1987-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Gombrich Themes Marle/Gombrich, 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Gombrich Themes (Lee's), 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - Gombrich Themes Marle/Gombrich, 1988-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
        - A Day on the Grand Canal Hockney/Haas, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-107)
      - [4 boxes of photos: 100 (2 groups of 50) of the Pantheon, 50 Trevi, unknown quantities of Cordoba, Neophytos, Maximilian, Hockney, Beauvais, Leonardo] (Box 2004.IA.14-114A)
      - Production Lab treatments:
        - Prod. Lab: Treatments (Master List), undated (Box 2004.IA.14-115)
        - Prod. Lab Film Synopses/Briefs, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-119)
        - P.L. Treatments 1, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-119)
        - P.L. Treatments 2, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-119)
        - P.L. Treatments 3, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-119)
        - [Production Lab Treatments], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-120A)
          [2 copies of each: Execution of Maximilian; The Fayum Portraits; Depiction; De Artificiali Perspectiva or Anamorphosis; Conversation with a Work of Art; Architecture of Transcendence; Ashes of Genius; Columns of Men; The Color that was Greece; Pleasure; Symmetry: Beauty in Islamic Design and Modern Physics; St. Neophytos and Icons of Wishful Thinking; Sir Ernst Gombrich; Pictograms; A Mosque in Time; The Monasteries; Mimbres Pottery; St. Genevieve, the Pantheon of Domes]
        - [Production Lab Treatments], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-120B)
          [2 copies of each: Ma: Space/Time in the Garden of Ryoan-Ji; Rafael to Eno; The Tempest; Thomas Rowlandson; Time in Michelangelo's Medici Chapel; Torrentius; Two Stories out of Space & Time; Fontana di Trevi; Halo; Proposal for an Interactive Videodisc; Judith of Bethulia and Narrative Art; Kashiwagi from the Tale of Genji; Leonardo's Water and Deluge Studies; Watercolour, practice and function; The Light Beyond the Sun; Velazques: or the Tears of Spain; Vermeer's Camera; Who Was Then the Gentleman?; Xanadu.]
      - Evaluation Process, Art Historians:
        - Evaluation Forms, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation (public) of PL films, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Guidelines for Evaluating Films…and single sheet, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation Guidelines, 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation of Films, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluating Interactive Media, 1993 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation: Research, 1985 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Out of Town: Evaluations, 1991 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation Panels, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation Panelists Past, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation Panelists: Resumes, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation: Peter (Possible Panelists), undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluations: Data on Films Screened, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Potential Evaluation Panelists, 1992-1994 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Prospective Eval. Panelists, 1984-1989 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Commissioning Guidelines, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Evaluation Forms, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Art Historians Master List, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Art Historian Meeting, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Art Historian Meeting, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Chicago Art Historian and Filmmaker Information Meeting, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Art Historian Meetings, 1986 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Various Information on Art Historians, 1986-1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
        - Art Historians Random Notes, 1987 (Box 2004.IA.14-100)
      - [Plaques, CINE Golden Eagle Award], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-117A)
      - [Plaques and certificates], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-117B)
    - Film and video, 1988-1992; Series I.C.2.; 11 Linear Feet
      These records are listed in the order found within the original accession.
      Records consist of films in a variety of formats, and one audio cassette, produced by the Program for Art on Film, 1988-1992 and undated. The films were produced for the series Art on Film/Film on Art. Multiple copies of each of the 14 films are included in the records.
      None.
      Technical Requirements
      Require video and film-viewing equipment.
      - [Videos: Art and Architecture (master), Artists and Architects Edit Master; American Architecture Now/Collaboration, Artists and Architects Edit Master], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-45)
      - [Videos: Beauvais Location Video, Part 2; Architecture of Transcendence: Bevals [sic?] Cathedral; Beauvais Location Video, Part 1; Beauvias [sic?] Cathedral (20 April 1988); Beauvais Cathedral (4/20/88); Beauvais Cathedral (9 mins, 6/29/88) (2 copies); Films: Architecture of Transcendence, film #3, 16mm Final Contact Comp. Print; Architecture of Transcendence (#8); Architecture of Transcendence; Architecture of Transcendence (#3?)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-74)
      - [Videos: Painted Earth: The Art of the Mimbres Indians (3 copies); Painted Earth (2 copies); Fayum Portraits (3 copies); The Fayum Portraits: Funerary Painting of Roman Egypt; Films: The Fayum Portraits (2 copies); Painted Earth: The Art of the Mimbres Indians (2 copies); Maximilian; 1867: The Execution of Maximilian], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-76)
      - [Maximilian (3 copies); 1867 (2 copies)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-77)
      - "1867" directed by Ken McMullen, undated; (1 reel: 16mm. Approximately 14 min.) (Box 2011.IA.52-01)
      - [Program for Art on Film, Four Films: 1. Leonardo's Deluge; 2. MA: Space/Time in the Garden of Ryoan-ji; 3. Painted Earth: The Art of the Mimbres Indians (8 copies); 4. Gombrich Themes (8 copies)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-79)
      - [St. Genevieve, Pantheon of Domes (11 copies); Pantheon Paris; Pantheon], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-81)
      - [16mm films: Gombrich: Reflections (mute check print); Gombrich: Illuminations, Reel 1 (2 copies); Gombrich Themes; Part 1, Illuminations in Art and Nature (very poor check print with many scratches and greenish color); Gombrich Themes; Part 1, Illuminations in Art and Nature (First check print from the CRI, USA liquid gate); Gombrich Themes: Part 2, Reflection in Art and Nature (check print from CRI (England)); Gombrich Themes: Part 2, Reflection in Art and Nature (very poor check print with many scratches and greenish color)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-84)
      - [Program: St. Genevieve, the Pantheon of Domes; A Mosque in Time; A Window to Heaven, 1867 (6 copies); Program: The Fayum Portraits; Trevi; Giorgione's Tempest; Architecture of Transcendence; A Day on the Grand Canal with the Emperor of China (9 copies); Program: Leonardo's Deluge; MA: Space/Time in the Garden of Ryoan-ji; Painted Earth: The Art of the Mimbres Indians; Gombrich Themes: Part 1, Illumination in Art and Nature, Part 2, Reflection in Art and Nature (31 copies)], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-105a, Box 2004.IA.14-105b)
      - [Gombrich Reflections (film, 2 copies); Videos: Gombrich Reflections Part 2 (2 copies); Gombrich, Illumination/Reflection, Sections, Rough Cut; Gombrich, Pt. 1 and 2, preliminary copy; Gombrich (3 copies); Gombrich Themes, Parts 1 and 2 (5 copies); Gombrich, Reflections; Gombrich, Part One (2 copies); Gombrich, Prog 1 and 2], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-112)
      - [Camera Originals, Conversation Shoots: Camera A (6 tape seris); Camera 2 (8 tape series); Camera 1 (8 tape series); Camera B (6 tape series); Unmarked video reel; Workprint; Audio Cassette], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-127a)
      - "Trevi" by Richard P. Rogers and Corey Shaff, with art expert John A. Pinto, undated; (1 reel: 16mm. Approximately 17 min.) (Box 2011.IA.52-02)
      - Published set of videos: Art on Film / Film on Art:, (Set of 5 VHS videorecordings. 2 copies of each.)
        - Program 1. Balance: Film/Art, 1992; (1 VHS videocassette) (Box 2011.IA.08-1)
        - Program 2. Film Sense/Art Sense, 1992; (1 VHS videocassette) (Box 2011.IA.08-1)
        - Program 3. Film Form/Art Form, 1992; (1 VHS videocassette) (Box 2011.IA.08-1)
        - Program 4. Film Voice/Art Voice, 1992; (1 VHS videocassette) (Box 2011.IA.08-1)
        - Program 5. Film/Art: Subject and Expert, 1992; (1 VHS videocassette) (Box 2011.IA.08-1)
    - Promotional materials, 1986-1998; Series I.C.3; approx. 2.5 linear feet 4 boxes
      These records are listed in the order found within the original accession, and by subject.
      Records consist of photographs, clippings, letters, and promotional materials for Program for Art on Film productions, 1986-1998. The promotional materials include press kits, testimonials and fan mail for all Program for Art on Film publications and productions. Multiple copies of almost all the photographs can be found in the records.
      - Photographs and related materials:
        - Lab Film: Still photo, general, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Photo captions, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - [Photographs, negatives, contact sheets], undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Trevi photographs, 1987; 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Trevi multiple photographs, 1988 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - St. Neophytos multiple photographs, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - St. Genevieve photos, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Pantheon multiple photograhs, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Mimbres multiple photograhs, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Mimbres photographs, undated (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Manet prints, 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Maximilian photos, 1992 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)
        - Cordoba photos, 1990 (Box 2004.IA.14-88A)